A Guide to the Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers Records, 1922-1985
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers Records, 1922-1985
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1992-027
ca. 1,000 cu. ft. 65 boxes plus oversize folders and approx. 1,500 rolled drawings
The collection contains project files and drawings related to more than 1,500 residences, churches, businesses, schools, and community buildings, predominantly in the Roanoke and Southwest Virginia area, designed by Smithey & Boynton, mostly between 1935 and 1957.
Smithey & Boynton, Architects and Engineers (Roanoke, Va.).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers Records were donated to Special Collections in 1992.
Administrative History
Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers, was an architecture firm in Roanoke, Virginia, established in 1935 by Louis Phillipe Smithey and Henry B. Boynton. The firm closed during World War II for a few years while Boynton and Smithey served in the U.S. Army. After Smithey's death in the 1970s, Boynton partnered with Kenneth L. Motley, who began his career as a draftsman with the firm. In 1992, a year following Boynton's death, Motley acquired Smithey & Boynton and renamed the firm Motley + Associates.
Smithey & Boynton designed several structures over the years, including the Christ Episcopal Church, the South Roanoke Fire Station, the Shenandoah Life Building, McClanaham Street Office Building, and the American Theater Building, all in Roanoke. The firm also designed Lane Stadium at Virginia Tech and the Lyric Theatre in Blacksburg. The firm became best known for building public schools, even using the same basic layout for numerous schools. Smithey & Boynton had nearly 150 school design commissions during the period of 1945 thru 1953 in at least 19 counties and 10 cities.
Biographical Note
Henry B. Boyton
Henry B. Boynton was born in West Chicago, Illinois, in 1899 and grew up in Amelia County, Virginia. He graduated from Virginia Polytechnic Institute with a B.S. in Agricultural Engineering in 1921 and a B.S. in Civil Engineering in 1923. Boyton then spent a year at the University of Illinois in Urbana taking architecture classes. He became a registered architect in Virginia in 1930 and later registered in West Virginia, North Carolina, and Pennsylvania.
From 1924 to 1928, Boynton worked as a draftsman at Carneal & Johnston, Architects & Engineers, in Richmond, Virginia. In 1929, he joined Louis Phillipe Smithey, Architect & Engineer, in Roanoke, Virginia, as an associate. In 1935, Boynton and Smithey partnered to form Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers, in Roanoke. Boynton became senior partner of the firm when Smithey retired in 1963.
Boynton was affiliated with the Virginia Chapter (later the Virginia Society & Blue Ridge Chapter) of the American Institute of Architects from 1938 until his death. He served on the board of directors in 1952, 1953, and 1956; as vice-president in 1954; and as president in 1955. He was a member of the State Registration Board for Architects, Professional Engineers, and Land Surveyors, as a Governor's appointee, from 1962 to 1972, serving as President of the Board in 1967. He received a distinguished service award in 1980 and the Noland Award in 1989, both from the Virginia Society & Blue Ridge Chapter of the AIA.
Boynton served in the Army Corps of Engineers during World War II, rising to the rank of Colonel. He was a member of the Virginia Tech Alumni Board of Directors from 1969 to 1979 and Chair of its Annual Fund Committee from 1973 to 1979. He also served on the Board of the VPI Educational Foundation, Inc., from 1978 to 1982. In 1976, Boynton received the Virginia Tech Alumni Distinguished Service.
Boynton died on September 13, 1991, at the age of 92, at his home in Roanoke.
Louis Phillipe Smithey
The son of William Rosser Smithey and Mannie Jane Elizabeth Greene, Louis Philippe Smithey was born in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, on June 7, 1890. He earned his bachelor and master's degrees at Randolph-Macon College in 1909 and 1910, respectively, and was an alumnus member of Phi Beta Kappa there. He was an instructor and special student at Virginia Polytechnic Institute from 1910 to 1914 and a special student at Massachusetts Institute of Technology from 1914 to 1915.
Smithey was a registered architect in Virginia and West Virginia. A fellow of the American Institute of Architects (AIA), he served as president of the Virginia chapter of AIA in 1940.
Smithey worked as a draftsman and contracting engineer for Virginia Bridge & Iron Company in Roanoke from 1916 to 1918. After serving in the army in World War I, he was contracting engineer for Virginia Bridge & Iron Company again in 1919 and 1920. He practiced as Louis P. Smithey from 1920 to 1922, as Smithey & Tardy from 1922 to 1927, and again as Louis P. Smithey from 1927 to 1935.
The Smithey & Boynton partnership formed in 1935 with Henry B. Boynton. Prior to World War II, the firm served as consulting architects for the Roanoke City School Board and Roanoke County School Board for approximately eight years and handled school buildings in Franklin County, Montgomery County, Alleghany County, Pulaski County, and the City of Waynesboro.
While the company was closed during World War II, Smithey served in the U.S. Army as Lt. Colonel from 1942 thru 1945.
Following the war, Smithey & Boynton were commissioned as architects or consulting architects on public school work in Virginia valued at approximately $31 million, distributed in 25 School Divisions of the state. Smithey retired from professional practice in 1963.
On June 11, 1938, Smithey married Dorothy Terrill, and they had daughter Nancy Terrill Smithey on March 10, 1940. He and his family lived in Roanoke. Smithey died on August 19, 1966.
Scope and Content
The collection contains project files and drawings related to more than 1,500 residences, churches, businesses, schools, and community buildings, predominantly in the Roanoke and Southwest Virginia area, designed by Smithey & Boynton, mostly between 1935 and 1957. Materials consist of project files, specifications, framed drawings and photographs, and architectural drawings. Records include designs by Smithey before he collaborated with Boynton, as well as designs by other firms of projects later redesigned by Smithey & Boynton. A small group of materials also relate to the firm of Johnson Associates International from 1968.
Please note: The list of projects/project files below does NOT include the rolled drawings currently being processed. Contact Special Collections for the current inventory of available drawings and how to access them.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: Series I, Biographical Information and Organization Records, 1923-1972; Series II, Project Files and Drawings, 1923-1985; and Series III, Other Architects-Johnson Associates International, February 1968.
Series I: Biographical Information and Organization Records, 1923-1972, includes documentation and administrative files on Smithey & Tardy, the firm in which Louis Smithey was a partner before the formation of Smithey & Boynton, as well as records from Smithey & Boynton. Materials include legal and tax files, forms and contracts for clients, biographical and personnel information, and some sample plans for school and residential designs.
Series I: Biographical Information and Organization Records is arranged by material type.
Series II: Project Files and Drawings, 1923-1985, is arranged in two groups by material type, project files and folded drawings. Both groups are organized by project number. The materials are for designs or renovations by Smithey & Boynton. The project files contain a variety of items and vary with each project. Materials may include small drawings and maps, contracts, correspondence and memos, and other documentation created by the firm or clients. Project files are listed with the project number, name, and location. The folded drawings are in boxes, organized in project number order.
Please note: Not all projects for which there is a project file have associated folded drawings and not all projects for which there are folded drawings has an associated project file. In other words, documentation on each project can vary.
Series III: Other Architects-Johnson Associates International is organized by material type. It contains materials on a single project completed by the firm: Farmland Dairies Inc. Processing Plant (Wallington, NJ). Files on this project are from February 1968.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Henry B. Boynton Papers, Ms1992-002
Index Terms
Persons:
Boynton, Henry B., 1899-1991; Smithey, Louis Philippe, 1890-1966
Corporate Names:
Johnson Associates International. (Architectural firm); Smithey & Boynton, Architects and Engineers (Roanoke, Va.).; Smithey & Tardy. (Roanoke, Va.)
Geographical Names:
Bedford County (Va.); Blacksburg (Va.); Buchanan County (Va.); Carroll County (Va.); Christiansburg (Va.); Covington (Va.); Franklin County (Va.); Montgomery County (Va.); Pulaski County (Va.); Radford (Va.); Roanoke (Va.); Russell County (Va.); Salem (Va.); Tazewell County (Va.); Virginia, Southwest; Wythe County (Va.)
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Contents List
- Series I: Biographical Information and Organization Records, 1923-1972
  Scope and Content
  Series I contains the internal documents of the architecture firm. Documents include professional histories of partners and employees, organization charts, sample contracts, and interoffice communications. This series also contains internal documents from the architecture firm, Smithey and Tardy.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Smithey & Tardy - Income Tax Returns, 1923-1927 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Smithey & Tardy - dissolution of partnership, 1927-1932 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Smithey & Boynton - Standard Forms and Contracts, 1939 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Smithey & Boynton - organization information, personnel data, and internal documents, 1941-1958 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Smithey & Boynton - biographical information and personnel histories, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Sample Floor Plans, schools (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Scrapbook - Sample Floor Plans, residential (Box 37)
- Series II: Project Files and Drawings, 1923-1985
  Series II contains project files and drawings for buildings consulted on and/or designed by the architecture firm of Louis P. Smithey and Henry B. Boynton. Project files can include correspondence, contracts, and building and materials specifications. This series also includes drawings and blueprints for projects.
  This series is organized in numerical order by project number.
  - #83 - Roanoke Country Club (Box 38)
  - #87 - Crawford, J. E., Residence (Box 38)
  - #88 - American National Bank; Roanoke, VA, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #96 - Presbyterian Church (Box 38)
  - #103 - Brophy, Mrs. No Lo, Residence (Box 38)
  - #108 - St. Paul's Reformed Church (Box 38)
  - #127 - St. Thomas Church (Box 38)
  - #145 - Wilson, Mrs. C. B., Residence (Box 38)
  - #170 - First Presbyterian Church; Roanoke, VA (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 38)
  - #174 - Lyric Theater; Blacksburg, VA, 1928-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9, Folder Project #174 - Lyric Theater)
  - #174 - Lyric Theatre, Blacksburg, VA and #191 - Salem Theatre, Roanoke, VA, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #175 - National Business College Alterations, Roanoke, VA, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #176 - Thomas, James E., Residence (Box 38)
  - #181 - Hardin, W. R., Residence (Box 38)
  - #188 - Jackson High School Addition (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - #189 - Wasena Grade School (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - #190 - Goodman, Dr. H. R., Residence (Box 38)
  - #191 - Salem Theatre, Roanoke, VA, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 14-18, Box 38)
  - #200 - A.M. Goodloe Residence, Roanoke, VA, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19, Box 38)
  - #203 - Covington Theatre (Box 38)
  - #204 - Dr. C.W. Boone Dog and Cat Hospital, Roanoke, VA, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20, Box 38)
  - #218 - Harry P. Stone Residence, Roanoke, VA, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 22, Box 38)
  - #219 - Dr. Gory Hogg Residence, Lewisburg, WV, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - #220 - Southern Chair and Novelty Corporation, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #222 - Mather Residence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - #224 - M. W. Paxton Residence, Lexington, VA, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #227 - W.M. Parker Store Building, Covington, VA, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 26, Box 38)
  - #230 - D.J. Phipps Store Building (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #236 - Ferguson and Funkhouser Store Building, Roanoke, VA, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 28-30, Box 38)
  - #238 - Elks Club Building, Roanoke, VA, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - #239 - Richard Wayland Company Building, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - #249 - Junius P. Fishburn Residence Alterations, Roanoke, VA, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - #250 - Salem High School, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #252 - H. F. Norman Residence, Roanoke, VA, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 35, Box 38)
  - #253 - Philip Baird Residence, Roanoke, VA, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 36, Box 38)
  - #254 - Stuart Moore Residence, Lexington, VA, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Jefferson High School, 1935-1941 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Lucy Addison High School, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Belmont School, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Crystal Spring School, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Gregory School, Gainesboro School, and Gilmer School, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Harrison School, 1935-1940 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Highland Park, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Jackson Junior High School and Morningside School, 1934-1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Lee Junior High School (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Melrose School, 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Monroe School and Jamison School, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Virginia Heights, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Wasena School, 1933-1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: Woodrow Wilson Jr. High School, 1933-1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools: West End Schools, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - #258 - Roanoke City Schools, 1934-1942 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - #258 - Jefferson High School, Harrison School, West End School (Box 38)
  - #258 - Lucy Addison High School, Gainsboro and Gilmer Schools (Box 38)
  - #262 - Jones, F. C., Residence (Box 38)
  - #264 - Barnhart Residence, 1933-1947 (Box 2, Folder 12, Box 38)
  - #264 - Barnhart Residence, 1933 (Roanoke, VA) (Box 38)
  - #265 - Christiansburg High School (Montgomery County, VA), 1934 (Box 2, Folder 13-14, 27, Box 38)
  - #266 - Blacksburg High School, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - #267 - Shawsville High School, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - #268 - Warrenton High School, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 17, Box 38)
  - #268a - Warrenton High School, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 18-25)
  - #272 - Parrott Residence, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 26, Box 38)
  - #275 - Mount Pleasant School, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 1-2, Box 39)
  - #276 - McCrum Drug Company Incorporated, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3, Box 39)
  - #280 - Mefford, N. F. Residence, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - #281 - Colored High School (Salem, VA), 1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - #282 - Greenbrier Baptist Church, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 6, Box 39)
  - #283 - Auto Spring and Bearing, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 7, Box 39)
  - #285 - Cambria School, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - #285 - Greenbrier Baptist Church (Box 39)
  - #294 - Glenn-Minnich Clothing Company, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - #296 - Mrs. C.C. Tutwiler Residence, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 10, Box 39)
  - #299 - Waynesboro High School, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 11, Box 39)
  - #302 - Jeter High School, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - #304 - Back Creek School, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 13, Box 39)
  - #305 - Covington High School, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 14-25, Box 39)
  - #306 - Christiansburg High School, 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - #307 - Shawsville High School, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 27, Box 4, Folder 1-2, Box 39)
  - Roanoke County Schools: #304 - Back Creek School, #309 - Andrew Lewis High School, and #312 - William Fleming High School, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Roanoke County Schools: #309 - Andrew Lewis High School and #312 - William Fleming High School, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - #309 - Andrew Lewis High School (Box 39)
  - #314a - Armory Building (Blacksburg, VA), 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 6-9, Box-folder Oversize box, Folder Folder 6)
  - #314A - Armory Building (Box 39)
  - #317 - Graves, K.D. Residence, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - #317 - Graves, Dr. K.D., Residence (Box 39)
  - #318 - Covington National Bank- Jewelry Store (Box 39)
  - #322 - Barr-Topham Company Store, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - #323 - Auburn School, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - #323 - Auburn School (Box 39)
  - #323 - Blue Ridge Overall Co. (Box 39)
  - #324 - Stone, Tile, and Supply Company, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - #328 - Blue Ridge Overall Company, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - #330 - Selma Grade School, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - #330 - Selma School (Box 39)
  - #331 - East Covington School, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - #331- East Covington School (Box 39)
  - #332 - Lindsey Residence, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - #332 - Lindsey, C.G., Residency (Box 39)
  - #338 - Clearbrook School, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - #338 - Clearbrook School (Box 39)
  - WPA Documentation: #338 Clearbrook School and #353 Andrew Lewis High School, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 20-21, Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - #340 - Lyric Theatre: Alterations and Additions, 1936-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - #341 - Stone Printing Company (Box 39)
  - #346 - Poindexter, Miles Residence, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - #355 - Jackson Memorial Hospital (Lexington, VA), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - #353 - Andrew Lewis High School, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - #353 - Andrew Lewis High School (Box 39)
  - #356 - Kepley, Charles Residence, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 8, Box 40)
  - #357 - Roanoke Photo Finishing Company, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - #357a - Camera Shop (Box 40)
  - #358 - Franklin County Jail and Courthouse, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 10-13, Box 40)
  - #362 - Luke, William Residence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 14, Box 40)
  - #365 - Consolidated Colored School (Covington, VA), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 15, Box 40)
  - #366 - Schooley, C.L. Residence, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - #368 - Whitlock Residence, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 17, Box 40)
  - #371 - Rice, H.B. Residence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - #372 - Blair J. Fishburn Building Alterations, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 19, Box 40)
  - #373 - Roanoke Country Club - Swimming Pool, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - #377 - Sutphin, S.D. Residence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - #380 - Garrett, W.S. Residence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 22, Box 40)
  - #381 - Jett, Bishop Robert Residence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - #384 - Auto, Spring, and Bearing Company, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24, Box 40)
  - #391 - Ring, Kirk Residence, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - #393 - Stone-Tile Supply Company, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 26, Box 40)
  - #399 - Rivermont School, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - #409 - Dorsey Residence (Roanoke, Va), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 28, Box 40)
  - #411 - Rockbridge County News Building, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - #416 - Waynesboro Colored High School - Gymnasium, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - #418 - Granberry Memorial Church (Covington, VA), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 31, Box 40)
  - #419 - Hunter, W.P. Residence, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - #421 - Roanoke Country Club, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 33, Box 40)
  - #423 - Esklund Beauty Shop (Roanoke, VA), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - #424 - Nettleton, H.H. Residence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 35, Box 40)
  - #425 - Boynton, N.G. Residence, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - #426 - Vinton Elementary School, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 37, Box 40)
  - #427 - Vinton Junior High School, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - #428 - Roanoke County Courthouse and Jail, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 39, Box 40)
  - #429 - Goria, R.A. Building, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 40, Box 40)
  - #430 - Roanoke City Armory, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 41, Box 40)
  - #431 - Williams Building, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 42, Box 40)
  - #432 - Charlottesville High School, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - #433 - Plank, Floyd: Lyric Theatre Air Conditioning, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - #437 - Southern State Corporation, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 45, Box 40)
  - #439 - State and City Bank Building, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 46, Box 40)
  - #440 - William Fleming High School, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - #441 - William Byrd High School, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 2, Box 40)
  - #442 - Southview School (see #446 in folded drawings for Southview School floor plans and elevations), 1938 (Box 6, Folder 3, Box 40)
  - #443 - Covington Armory (Box 40)
  - #444 - Blacksburg High School, Blacksburg, VA (Box-folder Oversize box, Folder Folder 1, Box 40)
  - #445 - St. Albans Sanatorium, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 4, Box 40)
  - #446 - Hollins School, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 5, Box 40)
  - #447 - Consolidated Colored School, 1938-1941 (Box 6, Folder 6-11, Box 40)
  - #448 - Covington Armory, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - #449 - Johnson, Gordon E. residence, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 13, Box 41)
  - #451 - Shawsville High School - Classroom Addition, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14, Box 41)
  - #452 - Clement, W.S. residence (Box 6, Folder 15, Box 41)
  - #453 - James, John P. residence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - #454 - Vinton Armory (Box 41)
  - #455 - Pilcher, Dr. John A. - Alterations to Office, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 17, Box 41)
  - #456 - Paxton, M.W. - Old Printing, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - #457 - Lunsford Residence (Box 41)
  - #460 - Traveltown, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20, Box 41)
  - #461 - Standard Drug Company - Campbell Avenue Store, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - #463 - Stegar, James Residence (Box 41)
  - #464 - Walker Machine and Foundry, 1939-1942 (Box 6, Folder 22, Box 41)
  - #465 - Roanoke Country Club, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - #467 - Pulaski High School and Dublin High School, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 24, Box 41)
  - #468 - Steger, James residence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - #469 - Vest, J. Harold residence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - #472 - Southeastern Finance Corporation, 1940 (Box-folder Oversize box, Folder Folder 3, Box 6, Folder 27, Box 41)
  - #473 - McAffee, Dr. William T. residence, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 28, Box 41)
  - #473 - First National Exchange Bank- Air Cond. (Box 41)
  - #474 - Grove, Dr. B.O., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - #476 - West End Real Estate Corporation, 1936-1941 (Box 6, Folder 30, Box 41)
  - #477 - John Russell Hospital, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 31, Box 41)
  - #478 - First National Exchange Bank, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - #479 - Vance Residence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 33, Box 41)
  - #483 - West End Methodist Church Parsonage, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 34, Box 41)
  - #485 - Betty Lou Shoppe, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - #486 - Morris Plan Bank, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 36, Box 41)
  - #487 - Elk's Club Building, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 37, Box 41)
  - #488 - Mount Pleasant School, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 38, Box 41)
  - #489 - Walker Machine and Foundry Shop, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - #490 - Bailey, 1939-1951 (Box 6, Folder 40, Box 41)
  - #491 - Eskelund's Beauty Shop, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 41, Box 41)
  - #493 - Huntington Court Methodist Church, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 42, Box 41)
  - #494 - Second Presbyterian Church, 1941-1947 (Box 7, Folder 1-4, Box 41)
  - #495 - Stephenson, W.D. residence, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - #496 - Johnson Chevrolet Company, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)